Keyur V. Patel

Carol Stream, IL | keyur5293@gmail.com | 630-290-0434 | linkedin.com/in/keyur-patel-7024a461

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

5+ years of experience as an Infrastructure Support Engineer with interest in troubleshooting Systems and Network challenges. Responsible for OS configuration using SCCM Server (Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager). IaaS (Infrastructure as a Service) and PaaS (Platform as a Service). Experience with Active Directory and load balancer for Microsoft Azure, Route 53 for AWS, and GCP.

EDUCATION:

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics & Communication Parul Institute of Engineering & Technology, India

May 2014

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Solution Architect
 Cloud & DevOps Professional Certification (for IBM Cloud)
 Microsoft Azure Administration (AZ-103)

May 2020

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Technical Skills Windows, Linux, SCCM, AWS, Microsoft Azure, Jenkins, CI/CD pipeline,

Github, Load Balancing, VNet Peering, Auto Scaling, EC2, VPC, Route S53,

Salesforce RemedyForce, Python, MatLab

WORK **E**XPERIENCE

Solvay Specialties Inc. India

IT Infrastructure Support Engineer

July 2018 - Feb. 2020

- Configured and managed organization Public/Private Key infrastructure using Active Directory and RSA Token for Laptop users
- Installed Systems and Applications Software on end user machines using SCCM (Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager) server.
- Configured MDM (Mobile device management) policy for corporate mobile phones
- Responsible for troubleshooting and diagnosis of hardware issues in Laptop, Desktop and network issues on server side
- Monitored downtime traffic of MPLS and iVPN links by using PRTG monitoring tool
- Hands on experience with RemedyForce ticketing Software in maintaining users queries
- Managed Inventory of systems, servers, network printers and documentation in Salesforce CMDB
- Single handedly lead the migration project of OS from Windows 7 to Windows 10 for 100 users
- Responsible for managing Network printers and generated monthly reports to track the print history of the users
- Managed and lead CCTV project where responsibilities included management of UTP cable, root
 of the cable laying from server room, installing additional racks for Cisco switch, and configuring
 dedicated ports and VLAN for CCTV
- Provided basic IT training to the employees such as requirements for creating and resetting strong password and explaining the prohibition of using personal USB drive in company laptop due to security reasons

Keyur V. Patel

Carol Stream, IL | keyur5293@gmail.com | 630-290-0434 | linkedin.com/in/keyur-patel-7024a461

Kochar InfoTech, India

Senior Desktop Support EngineerJan. 2018 - July 2018Desktop Support EngineerOct. 2015 - Dec. 2017Technical Support ExecutiveSep. 2014 - Oct. 2015

- Formatted, configured, and managed 800 plus windows and linux OS systems
- Handled password expired issues of the users
- Configured mail service for the users in Outlook, Mozilla Thunderbird and Windows Mails
- Used NMS Ticketing tool to manage user queries
- Configured systems in dedicated VLAN
- Monitored network traffic and downtime or fluctuation on NMT (Network Performance Monitoring) tool
- Helped ICICI Bank customers install and configure I-Mobile application

Project: Deployed a custom PHP multi-tier website on AWS with functionalities for SQL, NoSQL and file storage.

Technologies: RDS, SNS, DynamoDB, S3, VPC, EC2, NAT Gateways, Load Balancer and Auto Scaling **Accomplishments:**

- Configured AWS to send emails for every operation using the website
- Deployed the web application in private subnet with no internet access
- Used Auto Scaling for varying traffic workloads and Load Balancer to expose the application in the private subnet
- Used NoSQL database for metadata storage

Project: Deployed a website using Microsoft Azure

Technologies: Traffic manager, Application gateway, Virtual Machines, Blob storage, Virtual Network Peering

Accomplishments:

- Deployed the website servers in two different regions
- Controlled, managed and monitored the traffic geographically
- Enabled Path based Routing for the website
- Enabled communication between the servers Storing data on the cloud

Project: Developed CI/CD Pipeline to build and test a Website

Technologies: Git, Docker, Jenkins, Puppet, Selenium

Accomplishments:

- Set Puppet and Jenkins in Master Slave
- Architected Integration of Git and Jenkins for automated pipelines
- Used Puppet for Configuration Management Containerizing a Website